talend.com 2019-04-27

# Talend Website Privacy Notice - Talend Real-Time Open Source Data Integration Software

**Last Updated: December 31, 2018**

### Your Privacy Matters

Talend (“Talend”) is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. Visitors may access the Talend website while remaining anonymous and without revealing any personal information (except as referred to below under “Information We Collect Automatically”). Occasionally, and in order to provide relevant, desired information concerning products or services, Talend may request personal information from you. As a Talend website user or registrant, you are always entitled to ask any questions about this Privacy Notice by contacting:

Talend, Inc.  
Attention: Privacy Request  
800 Bridge Parkway, Suite 200  
Redwood City, CA 94065  
USA

Or:

Talend SA  
Attention: Privacy Request  
9 rue Pagès  
92150 Suresnes  
France

Alternatively, you can contact us at privacy@talend.com. Talend SA and its subsidiaries are the data controller of your personal information.

Because Talend is committed to protecting your privacy, Talend will not sell, rent or otherwise disclose this information to any third party, except as described in this Privacy Notice. Talend will keep all personal information private to the best of the company’s ability but some, personal information may be disclosed under the limited circumstances described below.

Talend is a global organization, with legal entities, business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross borders. This Privacy Notice applies to all Talend websites and domains (the “Website”), except that a Privacy Notice or statement posted on the Website specific to a particular Talend entity, program or service will apply in place of this Privacy Notice.

### Collection of Personal Information

 _Information that you provide_

To participate in certain activities and to obtain certain services offered on our Website, you will be asked to provide varying amounts of personal information. For example, we may ask you to provide your contact details in order to register an account with us, to subscribe to marketing communications from us, and/or to submit inquiries to us.  The personal information that you are asked to provide, and the reasons why you are asked to provide it, will be made clear to you at the point we ask you to provide your personal information.

 _Information we collect automatically_

In addition to the information you provide, Talend may also collect information during your visit to the Website through our automatic data collection tools, which may include Web beacons, cookies, embedded Web links, and other commonly used information-gathering tools. These tools collect certain standard information that your browser sends to our Website such as your browser type and language, access times, and the address of the Website from which you arrived at a Talend Website. They may also collect information about your Internet Protocol (IP) address, clickstream behavior (i.e. the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions you take in connection with the Website) and product information. Talend may also use some of these automatic data collection tools in connection with certain emails sent from Talend and therefore may collect information using these tools when you open the email or click on a link contained in the email.

Collecting this information enables us to better understand the visitors who come to our Website, where they come from, and what content on our Website is of interest to them.  We use this information for our internal analytics purposes and to improve the quality and relevance of our Website to our visitors.

For more information about cookies and similar tracking technology, please see the section labelled “Cookies”, below.

### How Talend Uses Personal Information

Talend uses your personal information to better meet individual needs, to respond to specific requests for information, to send promotional materials, and to make you aware of new or similar products or offerings in which you might be interested.  
Talend reserves the right to send registrants email communications (regarding product updates and promotional offers) from time to time in accordance with their communications preferences. You may opt-out at any time by (i) sending an email to [unsubscribe@talend.com](mailto:unsubscribe@talend.com); (ii) by clearly following the “unsubscribe” instructions at the bottom of any email you receive; or (iii) by contacting the privacy department at privacy@talend.com. To opt-out of other forms of marketing (such as postal marketing or telemarketing), then please contact us using the contact details provided above. You can also visit your [Email Preference Center](https://info.talend.com/emailpreferencesen.html) to determine and manage your preferences in term of communication you receive from Talend.   
In addition, to the extent you may be a business contact of Talend, please refer to our Talend Group Contacts Privacy Notice for information on how we collect, share and use personal information about our business contacts, and how our contacts can exercise their privacy rights.   
When it is necessary to do so, we may send you service-related announcements via e-mail regarding technical or administrative issues, legal notices or other important information about the Website and products and service considered valuable or essential to your continued ability to use them properly.   
Generally, you may not opt out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, please contact us by (i) sending an email to [unsubscribe@talend.com](mailto:unsubscribe@talend.com); or (ii) by contacting the privacy department at [privacy@talend.com](mailto:privacy@talend.com).

### What Information is Shared

Talend does share non-personal, non-individual information from which individuals cannot be identified and which do not relate to individuals in aggregate form with third parties for business purposes, such as consultants and advisors to the company. Talend will not disclose personal information to any third parties without your consent except in the following very limited circumstances:

 _Group Companies_

Talend shares information with entities within the Talend group. A list of our current group companies is available in Exhibit 8.1 of our 20-F filed with the SEC available at www.sec.gov.

 _Partners and Agents_

Talend shares information with trusted agents who provide specific services you have requested and/or administer information offered at the Website, for example, service providers who help manage, track and respond to customer inquiries, information requests, etc. Talend may also share information with authorized resellers and integration partners, who may be better suited to reply directly in response to your specific inquiries about Talend products and services. Talend may also share information with authorized resellers and integration partners in order to execute joint marketing initiatives. These parties do not use or otherwise disclose any information except as authorized agents for the purpose of providing the products and services that you have requested or administering the activities on Talend’s behalf, or participating in joint marketing initiatives with Talend. Any company that Talend shares personal information with will have executed a confidentiality agreement, requiring that they keep all data received confidential.

 _Third Party Vendors_

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering materials, sending postal mail, processing registrations or sending emails. We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

 _Legal Requirements and Investigations_

Talend will disclose your personal information to a third party if required to do so by law or if, in good faith, Talend believes that such action is necessary to: (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend the company’s rights and property or prevent fraud; (3) protect the company against abuse, misuse or unauthorized use of Talend’s products or services; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of personnel, users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false or deceptive registration information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you including your computer’s IP address – may be disclosed to a third party (including the recipient of an email) as part of any type of investigation into your actions.

 _IP Addresses_

An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer when you are using your browser on the Internet. The servers that operate the Website automatically identify a computer by its IP address. If Talend, in good faith, determines that you have used the service to menace, threaten, harass, intimidate or otherwise deceptively pose as another person, your actions will be investigated and your IP address may be disclosed to the recipient of any email, their legal counsel or representatives, and law enforcement officials as part of such an investigation.

 _Sale of Assets_

Talend may transfer its database, including personal information contained therein, to a third party who acquires all or substantially all of the assets or stock of Talend whether by merger, acquisition, reorganization or otherwise.

### Legal basis for processing personal information (EEA visitors only)

If you are a visitor from the European Economic Area (“EEA”), our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. 

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only (i) where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, (ii) where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights, or (iii) where we have your consent to do so.  In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contact with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). 

If we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), this interest will normally be to operate our platform and communicating with you as necessary to provide our services to you and for our legitimate commercial interest, for instance, when responding to your queries, improving our platform, undertaking marketing, or for the purposes of detecting or preventing illegal activities.  We may have other legitimate interests and, if appropriate, we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us using the contact details provided above.

### Linked Websites

This Website contains links to other websites. Please be aware that Talend is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. Talend encourages users to be aware when they leave this Website and to read the privacy statements of each website they visit that collects personal information. While Talend carefully chooses the websites to link to, this Privacy Notice applies solely to information collected on Talend’s own Website.

### International data transfers

Your personal information will be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you are resident.  These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country (and, in some cases, may not be as protective).

Specifically, our Website servers are located in the US and Germany, and our group companies and third party service providers and partners operate around the world. This means that when we collect your personal information we may process it in any of these countries where our group companies, third party service providers and partners process your data.

However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Notice, such as implementing the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of personal information (which require all group companies to protect personal information they process from the EEA in accordance with European Union data protection law). 

### Data Retention

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements). 

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

### Security

Talend employs appropriate technical and organizational industry-standard security procedures and processes to safeguard the confidentiality of users’ personal information. The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal information.   

Talend, or agents and partners on behalf of Talend, do everything in their reasonable control to protect your information. Where one of Talend’s partners or agents has access to or maintains sensitive personal information, the company enters into confidentiality agreements in order to ensure the privacy of such user information priori to sharing that information. Internally, access to all users’ and registrants’ personal information is restricted to those employees who need access in order to fulfill their job responsibilities. Furthermore, Talend employees who deal with user information are kept up to date on various security and privacy practice issues as they arise.

Finally, the servers for the Website are stored in a physically secured, offsite facility. Beyond the physical security of your information, Talend also backs up servers regularly to prevent loss of data. While the goal is to safeguard users’ and members’ personal information, Talend cannot ensure or warrant the security of any transmission and your information is submitted at your own risk.

### Cookies

We use cookies and similar tracking technology (collectively, “Cookies”) to collect and use personal information about you, including to serve interest-based advertising.  For further information about the types of Cookies we use, why, and how you can control Cookies, please see our Cookie Notice.

### Data Protection Rights

If you are a resident of the EEA, you have the following data protection rights:

  * If you wish to **access** , **correct** , **update** or **request** **deletion** of your personal information, you can do so at any time by contacting us using the contact details provided above.
  * In addition, you can **object to processing** of your personal **information, ask us to restrict processing** of your personal information or **request portability** of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us using the contact details provided above.
  * If we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can **withdraw your consent** at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * You have the right to **complain to a data protection authority** about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

### Notification of Changes

Talend may revise this Privacy Notice from time-to-time and reserves the right to do so. If Talend decides to change this Privacy Notice, the company will post the new notice on the Website or take other appropriate measures to inform you of the change, consistent with the significance of the changes we make. As policies are subject to change at any time and without prior notice, Talend encourages you to check the Website whenever you might have questions or concerns. If at any point Talend decides to use personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, Talend will notify users by way of an email to obtain consent to any material Privacy Notice changes if and where this is required by applicable data protection laws. You will still have the opportunity to elect not to have Talend use your information in this different manner. Talend will not use your information other than in accordance with the Privacy Notice.

You can see when this Privacy Notice was last updated by checking the “last updated” date displayed at the top of this Privacy Notice.
